Lately, six-figure wins and six-figure
losses are almost the new normal
nowadays where I can make four or five
hundred thousand in a single day and
also lose it like if nothing ever
happened.
But things weren't always like this. If
you would have met me seven years ago, I
would have asked you what type of donut
and what size coffee would you want. And
uh in that time period, I was a
consecutively unprofitable trader, a
struggling trader aspiring to be
successful where I lost $28,000 of my
savings and my family's money. [music] I
was unprofitable and doing all of this
by myself. So, I definitely understand
what it takes to go from absolutely
nothing to having major consistency and
profitability from the market. So, in
this video today, I'm going to teach you
how to optimize your current situation
and how to go from nothing to being at
the level where you want to be by using
$50. [music]
Don't underestimate the power of what
you can do with 50 bucks if you execute
things correctly and if you have a plan.
And in this video, I'm going to give you
a plan, a direction, and a strategy how
you can optimize it and reach your first
payout or your first successful account
flip. The realistic way, the no BS way.
Now, to get started, the first thing
that we need to do is analyze your
current situation and be fully
transparent and realistic about your
situation.
You're not going to get rich off of 50
bucks. You're not going to be a
profitable trader with 50 bucks. And
you're not going to have that
life-changing
dramatic shift that you're looking for
with 50 bucks. The best analogy that I
can give you is if, for example, you
were to be a fisherman. If you were to
go out to fish, you only have one rod,
one line, one hook, and one bait.
You really have limited resources. If
one fish hooks onto your line and it
snaps your line, you're done for the
day. So, you are going out to the game
or you're going out to go fish in a very
limited resource, so you need to tread
carefully and be realistic. And you
understand that you can't go and catch
extremely big fish with very small bait
and a line that doesn't have the
potential to reel in that fish. Trading
with 50 bucks is no different. You can't
expect to have 50 bucks be turned into a
billion dollars in 24 hours because
that's just simply not possible. You
can't expect to get a fifth 50 bucks and
buy extremely high leverage prop firm
account and get a payout in 24 hours.
You need to be realistic with your
situation. And this is the first and
most important thing because 99% of
traders fail because they have these
over overly
highly expectations of what they can do
with their current situation. If you
accept that this is your learning and
your building phase, you will get a lot
further than you can imagine. You need
to use these 50 bucks as a tool to test
out your strategy, your risk management,
your psychological battles that you're
going to face, and most importantly,
your plan. So, if you actually execute
these things correctly, then you can
scale with the small profits that you
make with these 50 bucks, whether
they're on a prop firm account, whether
they're on a personal account. And I'll
give this plan for you later, but you
need to have full clearance and
understanding that this is your building
moment. This is your learning moment.
This is not your scaling moment. If you
want to go out to actually
catch the big fish, you need to go out
on a boat to the deep ocean. You might
catch it from the shore, but not with
one line, one hook, and one bait. So,
now that we got that sour side out of
this out of the way, and you're still
watching this video, that's a really
good sign because it means that you're
willing to actually make a decision that
is going to slowly improve you so you
earn money from the markets, not make
money from the markets. If you're just
looking to make money, you will never
make money in the markets. You need to
earn it the correct way with the plan
that I'm going to share with you right
now. How to actually execute a correct
strategy with 50 bucks, how to scale
these 50 bucks to essentially a fortune
if you can do this the correct way, And
how to find a pattern that consistently
repeats itself in the time, and you can
use these 50 bucks to practice your
entries, your scaling in on this pattern
so where then you can execute on a
bigger account. So, with that being
said, let's get started. So, first
things first, this is going to be step
one to the actual plan on how to execute
with these 50 bucks.
Do not over trade. This is a quality
over quantity game. I get it, you want
to gain experience, you want to take
trades, you want to feel like you're in
the game.
You are not in the game by being in the
game. You're in the game by playing the
game strategically. And you do that by
executing the correct type of trades.
Limit yourself to two positions a week.
No need for any more of that. And every
single one of these positions, you need
to risk a certain percentage depending
if you go to a prop firm account or
personal account. I'm going to share
with that you later down in this video.
Write these notes down as key high-level
notes that you can always come back to
when you're executing this plan. So,
first things first, is quality over
quantity. Do not over trade. Now,
knowing that you only have 50 bucks to
trade with, again, we have limited
resources. We have to be realistic with
our scenario. Limiting ourselves to one
to two positions a week is going to
directly, by default, put us in a
category of the type of trader that we
are. So, when you're trading the
markets, you are a scalp trader, day
trader, and a swing trader. Swing
traders typically take one positions,
maybe two positions every two weeks. Day
traders can take one to two to three,
maybe four positions a week. And a
scalper can probably take 15-20
positions a week. You don't want to be a
scalper because a scalper is executing
too many positions that are low
risk-to-reward positions and have a very
inaccurate win rate because they're just
trying to enter a trade that can go in
and out of the position within a first
couple of hours. You don't want that.
You want a strong position that you're
following a trend and you're just not
looking for an impulse move. So,
scalping, out of the picture.
Swing trading is a great approach, but
the problem is you don't want to be
holding a position for days, even weeks
at a time, because it'll take a lot
longer for this 50 bucks to scale, and
the fees of holding these trades
overnight and holding these trades over
the weekend might eat into your current
balance, so it might not make sense. So,
we get that out of the picture. And then
we're left right in the middle with day
trading. So, the type of trader that we
are going to be, or the format of the
trade that we are, is going to be what's
called a intraday trader. So, it's a
trader that trades every other day. So,
that's where you where you would fall in
that category of one to two trades a
week. Now, an intraday trader enters a
position, should hit the take profit
within the same day or the next day. You
cannot control the market, so if the
trade doesn't [music] get there by the
end of the day, there's nothing that you
did wrong. The market is just simply
moving at the rate that it's moving.
It's important that you write this down.
It's extremely important that you write
this down in your notes, because once
you accept that, trading becomes a lot
easier. You could be following your
plan, but you have absolutely no control
on how the market's going to react to
it. You just have to be patient and let
the market do its thing. But we are
approaching the markets as a intraday
trader. Now, knowing what type of trader
you are going to be and the approach
that you have, you need to pick a pair
that you're going to be trading. Now,
there is dozens of different sets of
currency pairs throughout the market.
You have your major currency pairs,
which tend to be the safest markets.
They tend to be the [music] least
volatile, low fees, and quite
predictable. You have the majors, which
the majors are also mainstream markets,
a little bit of a higher fees, quite
predictable, but sometimes you can have
these random spikes. And then you have
the exotics. Exotics are very volatile
pairs. They move very aggressive, and
there's great opportunity, but also
great risk. Now, the type of trader that
we are trying to be with these 50 bucks,
you're not trying to be the most
aggressive trader. You want to find
patterns that are very predictable. And
what I'm going to educate you into this
video is a pattern that happens across
the entire markets, but you want to
limit it to a certain amount of pairs
that are the most predictable. So, you
want to dedicate this to the majors, the
markets that move very slow and steady
and the fees are out of this world. So,
these are the Euro USDs of the world,
GBP USDs of the world, all of the major
currency pairs that are cross
correlating with one another. And this
approach is something that we go and we
find in every single one of these
markets. We don't limit ourselves to one
pair because that one market cannot be
giving us that one pattern for a
duration of 6 months because the market
is just moving slow. So, if we limit
ourselves to just one pair, we limit the
opportunity of catching this pattern
that presents itself. It's almost as if
we were to have a very specific approach
on how to fish off of a pier. In order
for us to fish off of a pier, we need
low tides, we need a nice currents, and
we need for there to be a sunny day. If
we limit ourselves to one pier that it
doesn't have any of these conditions,
we're really limiting ourselves to the
opportunity to catch a fish. There's
hundreds of different piers that we can
travel to and look for that specific
condition in order for us to go out out
and fish there. Trading in the markets
is no different. If we limit ourselves
to one specific market, it can have bad
weather for a period of time where we
just simply don't trade because the
market isn't moving the way it should.
So, we don't care about the actual
market itself, we care about the pattern
within the market that whenever it
presents itself, it presents itself. But
we do want to limit ourselves to the
safer markets rather than going to the
higher risk markets. It's almost like
going to a pier that is very accessible
compared to one that you have to go
through, climb through some rocks, and
it could be a bit higher risk getting
there. So, now understanding the actual
trader that we're going to be with these
50 bucks, what is the plan with these 50
bucks? What do I do? I have $50. I want
to make money from the markets. Do I
deposit into a broker? Do I get a prop
firm? What is a prop firm? Which one's
safer? How can I not
We're about to break things down. Let's
get right into it. So,
this are your two options when it comes
to trading with 50 bucks. First option
is you can go to a prop firm. A prop
firm, you can buy an evaluation process
and you can get a payout. Or step two,
you go to a broker. A broker, you trade
your own money. You have a bit more
leverage on it. You have a bit more
freedom, but you really are limited to
the type of profits that you can make on
it. Now, there's pros and cons to both
of these and I'm going to let you decide
the plan for yourself. I'm going to lay
the options out on the table. You take
the information and you determine what
makes the most sense for you depending
on your situation. And I'm going to tell
you what I personally did and what
helped me scale. So, first option
>> [music]
>> is
prop firms. So, A Capital is a prop
firm. I flew out to Australia, met the
CEO in person, saw their office with
over 150 employees running this
large-scale operation of a regulated
prop firm.
If you guys are interested in getting a
prop firm account, discount code down
below. This is not an ad at all, but I'm
just being realistic because I back
their challenges because I believe that
they have some very cool and creative
stuff that would make the most sense for
the majority of the traders.
So, for example, with 50 bucks, you can
really get a two-phase challenge with a
$5,000 account. Meaning, you need to
pass an evaluation process. You need to
have your profit target be 9% for your
step one and then your profit target be
5% for step two. Now, this is quite a
lengthy process. I always estimate it
should take you anywhere from 30 to 45
days to pass a two-step challenge simply
because you should take be taking one to
two trades a week. If you were just to
have a basic 50% win rate, if you make
3% then lose 1%, make 3% then lose 1%,
make 3% then lose 1%,
that's roughly the 9% in about 3 weeks.
When you look at it in that math, you're
like, "Whoa,
that's kind of doable. That's pretty
realistic." Well, that's just phase one.
Then I give you another 2 to 3 weeks to
then pass phase two. So, you'll have a
winning position one day, have a losing
position the next day. As long as you're
profitable and you have a good risk to
reward, you'll be successful. [music]
So, that's for the two-phase challenge.
You have their custom day trader
challenge, which is quite cool, in my
opinion, because you can customize your
challenge where you're essentially
instantly funded and you get a payout on
what you have. So, if all we have is 50
bucks, we can even break this down to as
little as 5 bucks if you want to. But,
if you want to risk the entire 50 bucks,
this is like getting an instantly funded
challenge, where you have an evaluation
process for a duration of time.
So, you either have 1 hour to pass the
challenge, a 2-hour challenge, a 4-hour
challenge, or an 8-hour challenge. All
of these challenges, they just slightly
get harder depending on the hours that
you pick. So, the way it works is that
you start with a $10,000 starting
balance.
Whether you
decide to risk 50 bucks, 300 bucks, 500
bucks, your starting balance is always a
10K account. You decide how long you
want your challenge to be and what you
want your payout to be. So, if you pass
the challenge, you just get paid out
right away. There's no evaluation
process, there is no profit split, there
is no
continuation. It's just you pass it, you
get paid, you do it again. Very simple.
It's like an instantly funded account
with a one-time payout option. So, you
can choose to either have two times what
you decided to put at stake, you can put
five times, or 100 times. As you can
tell, the only thing that changes is how
much you get paid out and your drawdown
and profit target. So, for example,
let's say if you want to get 2x of what
you risked, all you have to do is make
$99
on the $10,000 account balance without
risking without losing more than 67%.
I mean, I'm sorry, $67. And then you'll
instantly get 100 bucks payout. If you
want to go 5x where you would get 250
bucks, you have to make 133 bucks
without losing 47. You want a 10K
payout, you have to make 239 without
losing 40 bucks. So, it slightly gets a
little bit harder where you have to make
more money without losing as much money.
And if you were to change the duration
of the challenge, things get easier. If
you were to have a 1-hour challenge,
your profit target is a lot less,
but so is your drawdown. If you have a
higher profit target, your profit longer
challenge, your profit target's a lot
higher and your drawdown's a lot lower.
Just a customizable challenge that I
wish I had when I got started trading in
my journey. And it's pretty cool. You
can mess with it. You can play with it.
You can see how it makes the most sense
with you. And then you also have what is
called the one-step challenge. So, I'm
just laying out the options right now
that are right in front of you and you
can decide for which one makes the most
sense for you. So, the other one-phase
challenge is the exact same thing. It's
a
total profit of 10% and then you have a
funded account. So, this the benefit of
both of these funded accounts is that
you could trade that funded account
continuously [music]
and continuously get profit splits from
it. The trader challenge is kind of just
a one-time payout and that's pretty much
it. So, the beauty of it is that you get
90% profit split, you can build your
custom challenge, and [music] you have a
lot less risk with a lot better leverage
with these 50 bucks. So, once you are
funded with that $5,000 challenge, let's
say for that next month you would make
10%. You would essentially keep nearly
450 bucks from that 10% that you made on
the 5,000. So, it makes sense to go the
funded route. The problem is that you
can be a profitable trader
but still not make money because you can
probably make on let's say this one-step
challenge, you can make a total of 5 to
6% where you're profitable, but you
enter a smaller to losing streak or you
just break a small rule where you risk
too much for a specific session and then
you lose your account.
Just because you broke a specific rule
doesn't mean that you're unsuccessful.
By the way, this prop firm has no hidden
rules. I did a whole YouTube video on
this. You guys can go check it out. I
talked to the CEO, asked all the hard
questions, and they answered. They
showed us the behind-the-scenes. You
guys want to go check it out, you can
see it for yourselves.
I did all the hard work before
partnering up with any prop firm because
I don't want you guys to go somewhere
that is not going to be a pleasant
journey and you simply just waste your
time. So, with this prop firm
the problem is that if you are a
successful trader, it won't show until
you get a profit split. And that goes
for any prop firm and any challenge.
Now, when it comes to trading on your
own personal account, there's pros and
cons. So, these are the trusted brokers
that I trade with. If you guys would
like to know more about it, link in the
description down below. I get it asked
every single video and I feel like it
sometimes you are blind. Like it's it's
right there, you know? So, the beauty of
having your own money in your own
accounts is that if you were to win that
first position that you execute with the
50 bucks, those profits are yours right
away. It's not like the prop firm where
you have to pass the challenge, do it
again, and till you get a payout, and
you need to just follow these very
strict rules. These rules are meant to
be in place for you to not break them
and be consistent. Now, with the broker,
you are pretty pretty just free-for-all.
Nobody's holding you accountable.
Nobody's setting limits. Nobody's
watching or caring what you're doing.
You're just taking trades at your own
free will, which could be good, but also
very bad because we all know when it's
us by ourselves in our dark room in
London session executing a trade, we
tend to just be impulsive. So,
there's benefits to this because you
have more buying power. So, you get
north of 100 of a 1 to 500 leverage
using these brokers because you can
execute trades as if you were to have a
$5,000 account. And you can have instant
withdrawals. So, if your first position
with this $50 account, you were to make
25 or 50 bucks, you can withdraw your
initial balance and then you're
basically playing with the house money.
So, at that point there's nothing at
risk. And the beauty and also
double-edged sword is that there's no
rules.
If nobody's watching you accountable,
who's going to make sure that you're
doing things correctly? Nobody but you.
And this is a whole other topic, but
these are just the options that I'm
laying out right in front of you. What I
would personally do, and this is what I
did,
I went, I got funded, I passed an
evaluation process. After I got passed
and I got [music] funded, I used those
profits and that knowledge and that
experience to then use my personal
accounts to scale. So, I would
personally start with attempting to pass
a challenge, get funded, get that
payout, use those profits to go and
trade my personal account. I would not
go and use that to go get a bigger
challenge simply because you fall in
that same realm. You got real money that
you just made and you're putting it back
into a challenge where you can
essentially be profitable, but still
fail because you broke whatever rule or
just because you had a small losing
streak. Where in your personal account,
you can have a losing streak, but you
can still have your account and have
equity in it as long as you did not over
leverage your account. So, let's
hypothetically say that you decide to
take the exact same journey that I did.
That journey is very simple. You would
go ahead and get your first challenge. I
would probably get a one-step challenge.
So, I would come here, go to the
one-phase challenge. I would go and
select buy now to get the challenge and
you would use the coupon code AlexG20.
You would apply that coupon code and you
would get discounted the 20%. We're left
with $55. Almost at the 50 bucks point,
but you would get your challenge and you
would attempt to pass this evaluation
process with the strategy that I'm about
to share with you. And once again, you
would use this profits that you would
make once you're funded to then go back
and deposit into your personal accounts
and then you scale exactly how I've just
mentioned. So, with that being said and
understanding that plan, let's now go
into the actual pattern that we're going
to be looking for so we can execute
[music]
to pass this challenge and then get our
payout so we can scale our personal
account. Now, we are at the end of the
preparation to actually execute the plan
with these $50. And the new plan and the
new approach begins. The new journey is
at this very point right here where
you're going to execute a very specific
pattern [music] continuously throughout
the duration of this challenge and only
stick to that. The problem with 99%
traders as to why they don't succeed is
because they don't stick to a plan. They
get tempted. They get FOMO. They get
greedy because they just want to take
every possible opportunity that they can
find in the market. The market rewards
the people that make the right
decisions, not the ones that execute
every single decision. You get rewarded
for taking the right trade. And this
right trade might not present itself
right when you're available. Might not
present itself today or tomorrow or the
day after. And you need to be patient
and wait for this pattern to present
itself. You get rewarded for taking the
right trade. The challenge is A cap does
not care if you are executing as many
possible positions as you can can when
the hour that you were free to trade.
They reward you when you win, and you
win by taking the right trade. And this
is the right trade. You just need to be
very patient to have this trade appear
and execute. So, the pattern that we're
going to be looking for with this is
going to be the famous head and
shoulders. So, the head and shoulders is
going to be the only pattern that you
are going to execute when it comes to
this account that you're trying to scale
with these 50 bucks. You're not going to
break your plan for anything. Head and
shoulders is a very simple pattern, and
it is what is called a reversal pattern.
So, this pattern, once you are having a
bullish market and you see it, means
that it's going bearish. Once you're
having a bearish market and you see it,
it means that it's potentially about to
go bullish. So, this works very simple.
A market that is bullish is heading to
the upside. It's creating structure. Let
me actually do this right here.
A market that's heading to the upside is
heading to the upside creating highs and
lows, highs and lows, highs and lows,
and then it it'll do a formation like
this, where might almost come as a
disguise. Right? Because everything up
to this point looks good. This looks
like a market that can just easily
create another higher high. You can
never predict a head and shoulders is
forming until it's actually formed.
Anybody that anticipates a head and
shoulders without experience is jumping
the gun a little bit, and they end up
taking the wrong trade and losing.
>> [clears throat]
>> Because in a position like this, it's
impossible for you to tell that this
next right shoulder is going to be that
reversal for this market. Yeah, this
just looks perfect to continue to head
to the upside. And that's exactly what
this did. This actually continued to
head to the upside and create a new
high. So, this market is very much
bullish. Now, the moment that we
create this what is called the potential
right shoulder. This is where you start
looking to be interested in this
position. Now, once we can tell that
this impulsive move is not going to
create that new high and it's slowing
down and it's looking like a head and
shoulders formation, this is when it
starts spiking our interest and we start
looking for this opportunity. Now, we
don't enter the position off of the
right shoulder because that is not a con
that is not a confirmed head and
shoulders right now. For all we know,
this could just be creating more
structure here before heading to the
upside and you just got faked out
because you entered on the position way
too early. So, you need to be interested
in entering this position once you have
a confirmed head and shoulders. How do
you have a confirmed head and shoulders,
you may ask? Very simple. This market is
being moved with market structure. This
is the higher high point
and then this is the higher low point
right here.
The head and shoulders, as if you guys
are paying attention, is a reversal
pattern.
Reversal pattern also means shift of
structure, chach, change of direction,
change of character, whatever you want
to call it. Something went from one
direction to the other. And the head and
shoulders is only confirmed once you
have that change of direction. So, once
this higher low
has been shifted and this market goes
from bullish to bearish, is exactly when
this will be a valid head and shoulders.
Now, this is a bearish market. This
turns into the new lower low and this
will turn into the new lower high. Now,
we are game. Now, we have an actual head
and shoulders pattern. The moment we
were
inside of this higher low,
if you were up to this point right here,
we are still not with a valid head and
shoulders. This is not a confirmed shift
of structure, chach, change of
character, change of direction, change
of identity, whatever you want to call
it. This is still a bullish market.
Looks like a really good head and
shoulders, but it's not a confirmed one
just yet. Need to wait for the full
shift, then this market turns to
bearish. This becomes the new lower low.
And after this becoming the lower low,
we'll have this turn into the lower
high, which is perfect. But now we have
a confirmed bearish market. Now is when
the actual strategy begins.
Which is our head and shoulders. Up to
everything before this, we were waiting
for this market to break, [music]
waiting for this to have the push down,
have the retracement, have the push
down. Now is when we actually [music]
start trading. This is where we start to
do our analysis and be interested in
entering this position. Everything prior
to this, it's just us sitting here,
twiddling our thumbs, and just being
patient. This is us sitting at the pier
with our rod in our hand, no bait on the
hook, not casting anything out. We're
just sitting there, waiting for the
current to start moving and for the sun
to come out. As soon as the sun comes
out and the current starts moving is
when we start to prepare ourselves to
begin fishing. Right there, we were just
at the ocean, waiting for an opportunity
to have our specific strategy where we
start casting out our bait, where it
starts to become worth it. If not, we're
going to risk losing the bait, which is
essentially lost money, and it simply
makes no sense. Uh everything up to this
point, we're just at the pier, we're at
the market, waiting for an opportunity
for everything to line up with us where
we were then to actually start to apply
strategy. It's a very cool perspective
when you think about it because fishing
and trading really isn't no different.
We both have plans on to what we would
do when it would make sense for us to
fish.
And I'm sure a lot of people aren't
successful fishermen because they don't
have a plan. They just go out there and
throw their bait and never catch a fish.
Uh this is know exactly why people come
to the markets. They just [music] take a
trade and don't succeed because they
don't have a plan, right? So, this very,
very, very similar. So, now that this
market has shifted bearish, we are game.
So, this is exactly where we would then
wait for this trade to have this
retracement, come back and retest this
neckline of the head and shoulders, and
this is where we would then execute our
position, where we would put our stop
loss, and then we would put our take
profit, and we would just set and
forget. Now, this
strategy can arguably have a 60 to 65%
win rate, sometimes more, sometimes
less. Depends how patient you are and
how well you execute this pattern. But,
these head and shoulders patterns are
very predictable and they happen all the
time. So, we're going to be trading this
on the major currency pairs, and these
currency pairs we're going to be looking
for this pattern strictly on the 4-hour.
So, for this specific strategy, we're
not going to take into consideration the
higher time frames, the lower time
frames, just looking at the 4-hour to
execute this trade. So, this is where I
can just go to one of my more recent
trades that I took on EUR AUD, and this
is a perfect example right here. As you
can tell, this market was bullish on the
4-hour. This market was creating highs,
lows, highs, lows, highs, lows.
We went bullish. So, as you can tell,
this right here is the higher high and
higher low.
This is the high point right here.
This is the higher low point right here.
And then, what we're waiting for is for
the market to shift below that higher
low. As you can tell, [music] if this is
the higher low point right here, the
market never really shifted into this
point right here. So, this is the left,
this is the head, and this is the right
shoulder. A bit ugly, you know, they all
of these aren't super pretty. Some of
them are a little bit ugly and they
create a bit more structure, but once
you get experience with it, you can see
the overall direction happen right in
front of you. This market closed below,
we shifted, retested, entered this
position with my stop loss above the
wick, my take profit to the next
structure point, and that is it.
That is your head and shoulders reversal
pattern formation. And I could have
continued to hold this position for a
significantly longer trade, but I
decided to close at my 1:2 risk to
reward, and that's it. And I can just
simply scroll left, and I'm sure I'm
going to find endless opportunities of
these head and shoulders that present
themselves. This is another perfect
example right here. For example, this
right here is another great head and
shoulders pattern. This market was
heading to the upside, creating that
bullish structure that we're talking
about, high, low, high, low, high, low.
This is the bullish structure. We
shifted, once we shifted, we retested,
and we sold.
It really is that simple. We are looking
for the reversal pattern. We wait for
the break, enter on the retest, set and
forget. Cannot get any simpler than
this. And believe me, I get it. There is
hundreds of different approaches that
they are out there. You have double top
formations,
uh ABC patterns, you have
uh Fibonacci's. Like, you have so many
different types of trading approaches
that you could go out and actually
execute, but we are not going to use any
of those. You need to have tunnel
vision. This is just You need to be like
a horse where you're only looking at one
specific approach and sticking to that
approach every single time you go
execute the position, and not get
distracted with the other opportunities
that you're executing in the market
because you're only looking for that
head and shoulders pattern. I don't care
if it's an ABC pattern, if it's a
Fibonacci, it does not matter. And once
you start to see this, it's almost kind
of hard to unsee it. It's like the red
car theory. You ever heard of the red
car theory? Where if you buy a red car,
you start to see red cars everywhere.
And prior to that, you never really paid
attention [music] to red cars at all.
But now, because you're aware of red
cars, because you own one, you see them
everywhere, and you're like, "Dude,
everybody has a red car." This is the
exact same thing. Now that you're aware
of this pattern and to only look at at
for it in the major currency pairs in
the 4-hour, you can just go to any one
of these major currency pairs and go
back. Go back in time. Just pause this
video right here or do it after this
video and just go back and you're going
to see these patterns and you're like,
"Wow,
I have missed out on so many of these
opportunities and I have just been
overcomplicating trading." Yes, you
have. It's totally normal. It's part of
the game. You're here to make a
difference if you're buying this point
in the video. You just need to be
consistent to this approach. Now,
understanding this very specific setup
that you need to be extremely patient
for to present itself, execute the trade
and set and forget. I want to build for
you guys a cheat sheet so you [music]
don't forget what you have to be doing.
I've seen countless amount of traders.
They start their challenge great, then
they get impatient halfway, and then
they lose it and they start right back
at square one. I don't want that to
happen to you because I want you to
succeed and I want to build you a cheat
sheet so you can actually follow this.
Now, step one on this cheat sheet, I'm
going to pop it up right here to this
side. First step is going to be to only
execute this replicable trade setup. Be
very patient. You know, it's that head
and shoulders pattern. Wait for that to
present itself. If you do not get that
trade setup, do not take a trade. You
are playing the game by not playing the
game but by knowing when to play the
game. This is very important that you
know this. Next point is going to be to
only enter after a confirmation. Do not
enter off of an anticipation. If you
have the head and shoulders that looks
like the most beautiful head and
shoulders in the world, if it is not a
confirmed head and shoulders, do not
execute [music] that position. You need
to wait for that position to confirm
that you have shifted. Next is going to
be to use certain psychological levels
in your favor. So, sometimes when these
head and shoulders break, they are
psychological levels like, for example,
80,000, 0.80,000,
or 1.0000.
Every psychological level is extremely
key to having a stronger trade. Does it
make or break it? It's almost as if you
were to go fish and you can almost see
the fish, right? It's a doesn't mean
that the fish is going to bite your
bait, but at least you have a better
feeling that the odds of [music] you
catching that fish are there. So, just
because you have the trade under or
above the psychological level doesn't
mean that you're going to win the trade,
but it's slightly better of a
confirmation. It's a very key to having
higher probability trade setup.
Next is going to be your fixed
percentage risk.
The most successful traders in the game
that have been in the game for 10 years,
they're not in the game [music] for 10
years because they won big. They're in
the game for 10 years because they never
lost big. You never lose big if you
stick to the risk management that you
need to be taking. So, have a fixed
percentage [music] on your challenge
account. Make it a 1% rule. Make it a
half percent rule. This is a marathon,
not a sprint. You want to earn your
money, not make money. Very different
points.
Next is going to be have a minimum of a
1:2 risk to reward. Do not take a trade
that is not worth the risk. You don't
want to make an even 1:1 of what you
risk. If you risk 10 bucks, you don't
want to make 10 bucks. You want to make
at least a minimum of 20 bucks. This is
a deal breaker when it comes to how well
you make back your losses and what will
[music] lead you to becoming a
consistently profitable trader. It's how
well you recover from those losses
because losses are inevitable and how
much profit is left on the table. So,
this cheat sheet, take a screenshot,
write it down in your own notes, print
it out, put it next to your computer,
put it as your wall screen, do whatever
you have to do so you don't lose track
as you're taking this challenge. It is
very normal. We are human. As time goes
on on week three, week four, you can get
a little bit impatient as you're seeing
other traders on social media making
billions of dollars off of taking the
same trades as you and you're in a
position there where like, damn, I'm
just risking 1% on my 5K challenge with
my 50 bucks. Well, if you were to have
paid attention at the beginning of this
video, you need to understand and be
realistic with your current situation.
Your current situation is temporary.
You're not going to be in this situation
forever
if you follow the plan. If you don't
follow a plan, you're going to stay in
that same negative spiral effect, and
you're just simply going to be walking
on a treadmill and not advance forward.
Because the people that are making all
this money, they stuck to a plan where
they got out of the position that
they're in right now, and then they
eventually earned the position that
they're in right now. And you can do
that for yourself if you do things
correctly. And this is what I do every
single week with my students inside of
my community. I educate them on how to
stay consistent [music]
with this very same specific approach
where they're executing the trades
according to the strategy, they're
engaging with other community members,
and most importantly, they're taking the
same trades that I am taking. If you
feel motivated and you feel that you
have a plan now to go out to the market
and pass this challenge, imagine if you
were to also have the same pairs that I
am interested in trading every single
week. Well, you can, because I do this
every single week with my students where
I hop on the famous Sunday Swings where
I share my top markets that I am
interested for that very week. What
markets I'm looking at so whether it's a
major, minor, or exotic, why I'm
interested in entering that market,
where is my specific entry going to look
like, where my stop loss is going to be,
where my take profit is going to be, and
then we spend all week discussing inside
of the community how this trade is
playing out. And I even have times where
I review trades of my students where I
can tell them, "Hey, you did this wrong
here. You did this right here." The odds
of you succeeding by having this proper
guidance
is just very high and very probable of
you succeeding. We're here at my trading
floor in Miami. I have built a compound
where my students only and exclusively
come out to to trading floor. They have
access and [music] phones that they can
trade with and also learn here in
person. But this is only to my students.
If you want to learn more how to
potentially be a student, click the link
down below in the description and apply.
It's an application-based
only and you might have a chance to be
part of the community and come out to
the trading floor. With that being said,
ladies and gentlemen, I hope you guys
enjoyed this video,
>> [music]
>> found loads of value. If you have to go
back and rewatch this video and write
down notes, do it. Don't get your
challenge, don't get this account
flipping and try and do it within the
first 24 to 40 hours. Understand that
this is a marathon, not a sprint. And if
you execute these things correctly for
the next 3 to 4 months, you will be in a
different position that you're in right
now. Because now you have a plan and a
very specific approach. Thank you guys
very much for watching this video. Hit
that like and subscribe button and I'll
see you guys in the next one.